



+639099959587



michelle.prado07@gmail.com



Pili, Philippines



www.michelleprado.info

## SKILLS

- QuickBooks Online/Xero
- Microsoft Office Proficient
- Inventory Management
- Accounts Receivable/Accounts Payable
- Bank Reconciliation
- Data Entry

#### PERSONAL STRENGTH

- Attention to detail
- Problem-Solving and Critical Thinking
- Time Management
- Strong Organization and Communication
- Integrity and Confidentiality
- Adaptability
- Proactive learner

# Michelle Prado

# BOOKKEEPER/CERTIFIED PRO ADVISOR

I have 7 years of invaluable experience in the banking industry, as well as the distinction of being an online bookkeeper, and I'm a Certified Xero Advisor and QuickBooks Pro Advisor. My experience in finance and banking has allowed me to develop a strong skill set in financial management; I take great pride in my meticulous attention to detail, ensuring that every financial aspect is handled with precision; and I prioritize maintaining the utmost confidentiality when it comes to client information.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### BANK CASHIER/BOOKKEEPER

Rural Bank of Pola, Inc.

2017-2023

- Cash and Transaction Handling.
- · Receiving loan payments and issuing official receipts.
- Recording checks, deposits, and other incoming receipts.
- Releasing loan proceeds after verifying complete documentation.
- Preparing transaction tickets for daily financial activities.
- Compiling and preparing the bank's payroll on a fortnightly basis.
- Maintain possession of and keep a record of accountable forms.
- Generating reports on bank transactions, including weekly, fortnightly, monthly, quarterly, and year-end reports.

#### **BANK TELLER/NEW ACCOUNTS**

Rural Bank of Pola, Inc.

2016-2017

- In charge of the daily collection and control of savings deposit.
- Preparing a daily summary of all financial transactions.
- Creating monthly and quarterly schedules of savings and time deposits.
- Gathering and recording essential information when opening new savings and time deposit accounts.
- Organizing and maintaining proper filing of all documents related to deposits.



# **EDUCATION**

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION -FINANCIAL ACCOUNTING

University of Nueva Caceres 2012-2016

### TRAININGS ATTENDED

# QUICKBOOKS ACCOUNTING SOFTWARE AND BASIC BOOKKEEPING

Pro Va, Philippines

#### 2023

- Bookkeeping
- Double-entry System
- Financial Reports
- Create purchase orders, Bills, record expenses and how to pay bills.
- Create estimates, invoices, sale receipts and how to receive payments from customer.
- Reconcile Bank and Credit Card.
- Prepare and generate financial reports

# AUSTRALIAN BOOKKEEPING WITH XERO ACCOUNTING SOFTWARE

Pro Va, Philippines

#### 2023

- Manage Customer Quotes and Invoices
- Manage Supplier Bills
- Use inventory for Products and Services
- Reconcile Bank Accounts
- Reports
- Xero Payroll
- BAS Preparations
- Australian Taxation

#### **DATA ENTRY IN-DEPTH TRAINING**

Pro Va, Philippines

#### 2023

- Data Entry Tools & Software
- Typing Skills: Speed & Accuracy
- Understanding Data Entry Process
- Creating and Managing Data Entry Forms
- Microsoft Excel
- Time Management & Productivity
- Data Entry Virtual Assistant Workflow